coinfinance.com 2016-02-10

# Bitcoin and alternatives cryptocoins news, prices and others analytics tools.

CoinFinance is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Please read the following statement to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of the CoinFinance website. The CoinFinance website is owned and operated by CoinFinance. If you have any questions regarding our privacy statement, please first contact us by e-mail at privacy@coinfinance.com. 

## Acceptance of Terms

Please read this policy carefully since by visiting the CoinFinance website and/or sharing information with us, you agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy. The Privacy Policy may be revised or updated at any time by us. This page was last updated as of the date at the top of this Privacy Policy. 

## Summary

Our primary goal in collecting user information is to enhance your experience on our website. Generally CoinFinance.com ("Site" or "we", "our" or "us") does not collect, store, use or disclose any data collected with an intention to personally identify and/or contact a person such as: name, address, telephone number or e-mail address (hereinafter "PII") except in specific instances, for example, when you provide PII through registering on the Site or as set forth in this Privacy Policy. Whenever we collect such PII, it will be governed by this Privacy Policy. Also governed by this Privacy Policy is our use of aggregated (data gathered and compiled across all user accounts) information, which helps us develop content targeted to users' interests and to better the website user experience. CoinFinance is committed to your privacy and, other than as provided herein or after receiving your specific consent, CoinFinance will not share any PII with any third party at any time, unless required by law or to fulfill products or services associated with this Site. 

## What this Privacy Policy Covers

This Privacy Policy covers the website CoinFinance.com and the transactions listed within this Privacy Policy Please be aware that CoinFinance sponsors, advertisers, and partners or affiliates who have co-branded modules or sections on CoinFinance may collect personally identifiable information about you while on our website. The information practices of those parties are not covered by this privacy statement. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Site. CoinFinance users should also be aware that, when you voluntarily disclose personal information in chat areas or bulletin boards, that information may be collected by others and may result in unsolicited messages from others. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. 

## Gathering of Information

### Voluntary Submission

CoinFinance does not collect personally identifying information about any individual CoinFinance website user except when knowingly provided by such individual. For example, we may ask you for information, such as your e-mail address, title and industry when you register to become a member of CoinFinance. You may also provide information to CoinFinance in other contexts, including, for example, in order to register for the Stock Simulator or to enter into a sweepstakes or promotion. In the event you order something from CoinFinance or one of our co-branded websites, we may request additional personal information, such as your address, telephone number and payment information, in order to complete the purchase. In order to further enhance the website user experience and target content to users’ interests, we may also supplement the data you provide to us with data from data append services (where other information may be added to the information you provide). You always have the option not to provide the information we request. If you choose not to provide the information we request, you can still visit most of the CoinFinance website, but you may be unable to access certain options and services. When you register or become a member of CoinFinance or provide information to CoinFinance in any other manner, you agree to provide only true, accurate, current and complete information. 

### Cookies

A cookie is a small data file that is written to your computer's hard drive by your web browser. A cookie file can contain information, such as a user identification code, that a website will use to track the pages and number of times you have visited. CoinFinance uses cookies to track web and advertising analytics throughout CoinFinance and its affiliate websites and to remember your custom video playlists, preferences, job title, story ratings (if you have provided any), and membership status so that you don't have to login each time you visit the website. The data read from these cookies may be linked to personally identifying (PII) and non-personally identifying (non-PII) information.   
We also use browser plug-in cookies on our site, including Flash cookies, also known as "local shared objects," to perform similar functions as browser cookies. Like normal browser cookies, these cookies are represented as small files stored on your computer. One method of preventing Flash cookies from being placed is to adjust your preferences in the Macromedia Website Privacy Settings Panel at macromedia.com.   
Business partners of CoinFinance, vendors providing hosting and other services for CoinFinance, third party analytics providers, as well as advertisers who contract directly with a third-party service to serve their advertisements on our website may set their own unique cookies through your browser. We do not have access to these cookies or any information that they may contain. All such third-party cookies are not governed by this Privacy Policy, but by the privacy policy of such third party. If you would like more information about this practice and about your option not to accept cookies placed by these companies, please click here.   
Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser settings to display a warning before accepting a cookie, choose to accept cookies only from certain websites or to refuse all cookies. However, if you choose to disable the receipt of cookies from our website, you may not be able to use certain features of the site. To learn more about the use of cookies in online advertising including how to manage or delete them click here.   

### Web Beacons

We use web beacons (invisible images often referred to as pixel tags or clear GIFs) on our sites in order to recognize users, assess traffic patterns, identify preferred content and measure site engagement. We also include web beacons in our e-mail messages, including newsletters, in order to count how many e-mail messages have been opened. 

### Log Files

CoinFinance web and ad servers log information about a site user's IP address, browser type and the current URL the user is requesting. This information is always provided by each and every user's browser. These log files are stored in a secure location and may be used in an anonymous manner in our internal analysis of traffic patterns within our website and with specific third parties contracted by CoinFinance. This information is automatically logged by most websites. 

### Widgets

Widgets are small content modules that users can embed on their own sites. We offer widgets that are hosted on CoinFinance, like our embeddable video player, as well as widgets that are powered by 3rd party vendors. Use of the CoinFinance widgets is subject to the CoinFinance terms of use, but downloading or embedding these widgets on other websites is not covered by this privacy statement. 

### Use of Information

Our primary goal in collecting user information is to enhance your experience on our website. 

### To Target Content and Advertising

To develop and provide content and advertising to you that is targeted to your interests, we use the analytics collected by the systems described above to determine which areas of our website you prefer based upon the frequency of your visits and engagement with those areas. We may also make reasonable geographic and demographic assumptions based on your presented IP address to target relevant content and advertising.   
The Non-PII collected by such parties on our Site and other websites may be used in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, please click on the following link: NAI Website. Although we choose our business partners and clients carefully, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such third parties. You should check the applicable privacy policies of these third-party advertisers to determine how they handle any information they collect from you.   
To Provide Interactive Communications From CoinFinance.com   
To enhance your experience we may provide you with interactive communications, such as our electronic newsletters, to the e-mail address that you provide to us. Such interactive communications are provided only to those users who have expressly provided us with their permission to receive them as part of their user profile.   
From time to time we may provide e-mails highlighting new features, promotions or contests on the website to those users who have expressly provided us with their permission to send such communications as part of their user profile.   

### Control of Your Information

Registered users may change the information stored in their member profile such as e-mail address, zip code, country, title and industry, and they may elect to stop receiving newsletters or marketing material from CoinFinance or on behalf of external third party business partners. Users may choose to stop receiving such communications at any time by visiting the "To unsubscribe or change your email settings" link found at the end of any such e-mail received. 

### Sharing of Information

#### Technical Services

We use third parties to provide processing, e-mail service providers and hosting services on our site. When you are on an area of CoinFinance and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with CoinFinance as well as business partners and vendors providing hosting and other services for CoinFinance. When you sign up for such services, we will share your personally identifiable information as necessary for the third party to provide that service. These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose. If you do not want your information to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer of your information by not using that particular service.   
In addition, if you provide any personally identifiable information via an advertiser promotion, please be aware you are directly providing your personally identifiable information to that advertiser.   

#### Contests or Surveys

From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you, such as your name and e-mail. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. We use this personally identifiable information to notify contest winners and award prizes. We may use a third party service provider to conduct these surveys or contests; that company will be prohibited from using our users personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We will not share the personally identifiable information you provide through a contest or survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice. 

#### Email Referral

We also have features that allow you to send an e-mail to yourself and/or others about an item on our site. If you choose to use our e-mail referral service, you will be required to provide the e-mail address or addresses that will be used in the notification. Upon form submission an e-mail will be generated to your recipient(s) inviting them to visit the URL you have recommended. We do not store this information other than for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail. 

#### Aggregate, Anonymous Information With Advertisers

CoinFinance derives the majority of its revenue from advertising and sharing information is essential to keeping our services affordable to users. In order to attract and retain advertisers we use the aggregated, anonymous information that we gather (as well as information from third-party market researchers) to describe our services to partners and to assist our advertisers and sponsors to better understand our audience. We do not disclose personally identifying information about our users to these parties. 

#### As Necessary to Provide Services to You

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of newsletter mailings, processing transactions, or performing statistical analysis of our services. We will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service. In some instances these companies may collect information directly from you (such as for credit card processing for the purchase of investment newsletters). In these cases, you will be notified of the involvement of the external service provider. In all cases, these companies are subject to agreements that require them to maintain the confidentiality of your information and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose. 

#### In The Event of Sale or Bankruptcy

The ownership of CoinFinance may change at some point in the future. Should that occur, we want this site to be able to maintain a relationship with you. In the event of a sale, merger, public offering, bankruptcy or other change in control of CoinFinance your information may be shared with the person or business that owns or controls this site. Opting out of receiving information from third parties will not affect our right to transfer your information to a new owner, but your choices will continue to be respected regarding the use of your information. You will be notified as described below in "How will I know if the Privacy Policy is changed." 

#### As Required By Law

CoinFinance may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or legal process served on CoinFinance or to protect and defend the rights or property of CoinFinance. 

#### Security

Your information is stored on CoinFinance's servers located in the United States. We use industry standard procedural and technical safeguards to protect your personal information against loss or theft as well as unauthorized access and disclosure to protect your privacy, including encryption, "firewalls" and the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). We treat data as an asset that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. We employ many different security techniques to protect such data from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the company. However, "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet and you acknowledge and agree to assume this risk when communicating with us.
